<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string-array name="soil_names">
        <item>Alpine soils</item>
        <item>Anthrosol</item>
        <item>Arenosols</item>
        <item>Cambisol</item>
        <item>Cambisols (Alumic)</item>
        <item>Cambisols (Clayic)</item>
        <item>Cambisols (Dystric)</item>
        <item>Cambisols (Eutric)</item>
        <item>Cambisols and Leptosols</item>
        <item>Cambisols and Podzols on terrace sediments</item>
        <item>Entic Podzols and Podzols</item>
        <item>Fluvisols</item>
        <item>Gleyic Chernozems</item>
        <item>Gleysols</item>
        <item>Histosols</item>
        <item>Chernozems</item>
        <item>Chernozems and Gleyic Chernozems</item>
        <item>Leptosol (Calcaric)</item>
        <item>Luvic Greyic Phaeozems</item>
        <item>Luvisols</item>
        <item>Podzols</item>
        <item>Rendzic Leptosols</item>
        <item>Retisols and Stagnic Retisols</item>
        <item>Saline soils</item>
        <item>Stagnosols and Stagnic Cambisols</item>
        <item>Technosols</item>
        <item>Vertisols</item>



    </string-array>

    <string-array name="soil_texts">
        <item>Alpine soils are located above the upper border of the forest with shrubs in the Czech Republic (e.g. Giant Mountains, Bohemian Forest).</item>

        <item>An anthrosol (or anthropogenic soil) in the World Reference Base for Soil Resources (WRB) is a type of soil that has been formed or heavily modified due to long-term human activity, such as from irrigation, addition of organic waste or wet-field cultivation used to create paddy fields.
        \n\n
            Such soils can be formed from any parent soil, and are commonly found in areas where agriculture has been practised for centuries. Anthrosols can be found worldwide, though they tend to have different soil horizons in different regions. For example, in northwestern Europe anthrosols commonly have plaggic or terric (strongly affected by manure) horizons, and together they cover some 500,000 hectares.
        </item>

        <item>Arenosols, regozemě, kambizemě a podzoly arenické</item>

        <item>Cambisols are characterized by the absence of a layer of accumulated clay, humus, soluble salts, or iron and aluminum oxides. They differ from unweathered parent material in their aggregate structure, colour, clay content, carbonate content, or other properties that give some evidence of soil-forming processes. Because of their favourable aggregate structure and high content of weatherable minerals, they usually can be exploited for agriculture subject to the limitations of terrain and climate. Cambisols are the second most extensive soil group on Earth, occupying 12 percent of the total continental land area—mainly in boreal polar regions, in landscapes with high rates of erosion, and in regions of parent material resistant to clay movement. They are not common in humid tropical climates.</item>

        <item>
            Cambisols (Alumic) are highly saturated with aluminum (more than 30%), agricultural soils have a saturation of the horizon Bv up to 30%, forest soils up to 20%.
        </item>

        <item>Cambisols (Clayic), pelozemě</item>

        <item>Cambisols (Dystric), kambizemě kyselé</item>

        <item>Cambisols (Eutric), kambizemě eutrofní</item>

        <item>Cambisols and Leptosols, kambizemě s rankery a litozeměmi</item>

        <item>Cambisols and Podzols on terrace sediments, they are evolved on fluvial deposits of running water. Fluvial deposit are one of the most important sediments, as it forms a continuous system of terrace accumulations along river flows.
        \n\n
        A classic example of the terraces in the Czech Republic are terraces in the vicinity of Vltava or Elbe rivers.
        </item>

        <item>Entic Podzols and Podzols, kryptopodzoly s podzoly</item>

        <item>Fluvisols, fluvizemě</item>

        <item>Gleyic Chernozems, Černice</item>

        <item>A Gley is a wetland soil (hydric soil) that, unless drained, is saturated with groundwater for long enough periods to develop a characteristic gleyic colour pattern. This pattern is essentially made up of reddish, brownish, or yellowish colours at surfaces of soil particles and/or in the upper soil horizons mixed with greyish/blueish colours inside the peds and/or deeper in the soil. Gleysols are also known as Gleyzems, meadow soils, Aqu-suborders of Entisols, Inceptisols and Mollisols (USDA soil taxonomy), or as groundwater soils and hydro-morphic soils.
\n\n
Gleysols occur within a wide range of unconsolidated materials, mainly fluvial, marine and lacustrine sediments of Pleistocene or Holocene age, having basic to acidic mineralogy. They are found in depression areas and low landscape positions with shallow groundwater.
        \n\n
        Source: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gleysol
        </item>


        <item>Histosol is a soil consisting primarily of organic materials. They are defined as having 40 centimetres or more of organic soil material in the upper 80 centimetres. Organic soil material has an organic carbon content (by weight) of 12 to 18 percent, or more, depending on the clay content of the soil. These materials include muck (sapric soil material), mucky peat (hemic soil material), or peat (fibric soil material). Aquic conditions or artificial drainage are required. Typically, Histosols have very low bulk density and are poorly drained because the organic matter holds water very well. Most are acidic and many are very deficient in major plant nutrients which are washed away in the consistently moist soil.
           \n\n
Histosols form whenever organic matter forms at a more rapid rate than it is destroyed. This occurs because of restricted drainage precluding aerobic decomposition, and the remains of plants and animals remain within the soil. Thus, Histosols are very important ecologically because they store large quantities of organic carbon. If accumulation continues for a long enough period, coal forms.
            \n\n
            Histosols are generally very difficult to cultivate because of the poor drainage and often low chemical fertility. However, Histosols formed on very recent glacial lands can often be very productive when drained and produce high-grade pasture for dairying or beef cattle. They can sometimes be used for fruit if carefully managed, but there is a great risk of the organic matter becoming dry powder and eroding under the influence of drying winds. A tendency towards shrinkage and compaction is also evident with crops.
         \n\n
        Source: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Histosol
        </item>

        <item>Chernozem (from Russian: chernozyom; "black soil") is a black-colored soil containing a high percentage of humus (4% to 16%) and high percentages of phosphoric acids, phosphorus, and ammonia. Chernozem is very fertile and can produce high agricultural yields with its high moisture storage capacity. Chernozems are also a Reference Soil Group of the World Reference Base for Soil Resources (WRB).</item>

        <item>Chernozems and Gleyic Chernozems, černozemě s černicemi</item>

        <item>Leptosol (Calcaric), pararendziny</item>

        <item>Luvic Greyic Phaeozems, šedozemě</item>

             <item>Luvisol has the mixed mineralogy, high nutrient content, and good drainage of these soils make them suitable for a wide range of agriculture, from grains to orchards to vineyards. Luvisols form on flat or gently sloping landscapes under climatic regimes that range from cool temperate to warm Mediterranean. Occupying just over 5 percent of the total continental land area on Earth, they are found typically in west-central Russia, the United States, central Europe, the Mediterranean basin, and southern Australia.
           \n\n
Luvisols are technically characterized by a surface accumulation of humus overlying an extensively leached layer that is nearly devoid of clay and iron-bearing minerals. Below the latter lies a layer of mixed clay accumulation that has high levels of available nutrient ions comprising calcium, magnesium, sodium, or potassium. Luvisols are often associated with Cambisols. Albeluvisols are a related FAO soil group also exhibiting clay migration.
        </item>

        <item>In soil science, podzols are the typical soils of coniferous or boreal forests. In Western Europe, podzols develop on heathland, which is often a construct of human interference through grazing and burning. In some British moorlands with podzolic soils, cambisols are preserved under Bronze Age barrows.
           \n\n
Podzol means "under-ash" and is derived from the Russian под (pod) + зола́ (zola); the full form is "подзо́листая по́чва" (podzolistaya pochva, "under-ashed soil"). The term was first given in middle of 1875 by Vasily Dokuchaev. It refers to the common experience of Russian peasants of plowing up an apparent under-layer of ash (leached or E horizon) during first plowing of a virgin soil of this type.
            \n\n
Podzols can occur on almost any parent material but generally derive from either quartz-rich sands and sandstone or sedimentary debris from magmatic rocks, provided there is high precipitation. Most Podzols are poor soils for agriculture due to the sandy portion, resulting in a low level of moisture and nutrients. Some are sandy and excessively drained. Others have shallow rooting zones and poor drainage due to subsoil cementation. A low pH further compounds issues, along with phosphate deficiencies and aluminum toxicity. The best agricultural use of Podzols is for grazing, although well-drained loamy types can be very productive for crops if lime and fertilizer are used.
         \n\n
The E horizon, which is usually 4 to 8 centimetres thick, is low in Fe and Al oxides and humus. It is formed under moist, cool and acidic conditions, especially where the parent material, such as granite or sandstone, is rich in quartz. It is found under a layer of organic material in the process of decomposition, which is usually 5 to 10 centimetres thick. In the middle, there is often a thin horizon of 0.5 to 1 centimetre. The bleached soil horizon goes over into a red or red-brown horizon (so-called Podzolic B). The colour is strongest in the upper part, and change at a depth of 50 to 100 centimetres progressively to the part of the soil that is mainly not affected by processes; that is the parent material. The soil profiles are designated by the letters A (topsoil), E (eluviated soil), B (subsoil) and C (parent material).
        </item>

        <item>Rendzic Leptosols, rendziny</item>

        <item>Retisols and Stagnic Retisols, luvizemě s luvizeměmi oglejenými</item>

        <item>Saline soils, zasolené půdy</item>

        <item>Stagnosols and Stagnic Cambisols are soils referred as pseudoglej in Czech. Stagnosol is a soil type widespread throughout the Czech Republic, mainly in the Tertiary basins (around cities Cheb, Třeboň, České Budějovice). Stagnosols have periodically over-wetting and drying of the soil profile, they arise mainly in places of terrain depressions and in flooded areas around rivers. Due to this, their occurrence is limited to approximately a maximum altitude of 800 meters. In lower positions, they are formed mainly on heavy soil-forming substrates. With increasing altitude, they also occur on medium or light substrates.</item>

        <item>Technosols, antropogenní půdy</item>

        <item>Vertisols, smonice</item>

    </string-array>

</resources>